MUHAMMAD SULTAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

GET IN CONTACT

Mobile: 03113696218

Email: m.shykh@outlook.com

Linkdin:

linkedin.com/in/muhammad-

sultan-62b447143

Address:

Garden East, Karachi, Pakistan

PERSONAL PROFILE

An emerging software engineer, looking to apply my problem-solving and technical skills in a challenging and dynamic environment, I have been a level 1 seller at Fiver with a 2-year of experience in freelancing and a 1-year experience in the industry, my skills include fluency in full-stack web development with ASP,NET MVC and Core PHP and eager to help companies with emerging obstacles.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Hands on experience in full stack web development and database design with:

- HTML
- jQuery
- Ajax
- PHP
- ASP.NET MVC
- C#
- MySQL
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Oracle SQL Database
- MongoDB
- Angular Js
- UmbracoCMS
- Microsoft Office
- Version Control using Git
- OOP
- Debugging

WORK EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Deviniti Private Limited June 1st 2021 to Present

FREELANCER

Upwork | Feb 2021 to Present

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~012daa6e0a9e963307

LEVEL 1 SELLER

Fiverr | Nov 2019 to Present

https://www.fiverr.com/sultanshaikh77

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Nanosoft Technologies | 9-12-20 to 26-03-20

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Intellexal Solutions Private Limited 10-06-2019 to 28-06-2019

OTHER SKILLS

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design and implement database structures
- Detail oriented
- Excellent problem solver

EDUCATION HISTORY

MEHRAN UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY Bachelor of Software Engineering, 2020 CGPA: 3.84

- Coursework in web development, database management, object-oriented programming in java, android programming.

PROJECTS

- Zong Masking Portal
- Web Portal for Teacher Welfare Council
- Face Recognition System on Python
- My Portfolio Website
- OPS Law WebApp
- Online Student Portal on Android
- Student Consultancy Web App
- Student Management System on Java

LICENSE AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Freelancing | Digiskills.pk
- Building Web Applications in PHP | Coursera
- Projects in Csharp | Eduonix Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd
- Wordpress | Digiskills.pk